const question = document.querySelector('#question');
const choices = Array.from(document.querySelectorAll('.choice-text'));
const progressText = document.querySelector('#progressText');
const scoreText = document.querySelector('#score');
const progressBarFull = document.querySelector('#progressBarFull');

let currentQuestion = {}
let acceptingAnswers = true
let score = 0
let questionCounter = 0
let availableQuestions = []

let questions = [

    {
        question:
        "1. Which of the following accurately describes a P device?",
        choice1: ' It is used exclusively by the customer.',
        choice2: ' It is responsible for adding and removing labels.',
        choice3: ' It swaps label information and forwards packets.',
        choice4: ' It creates an LSP in the provider network.',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "2. Which of the following is false regarding an SDP?",
        choice1: ' It provides transport tunnel encapsulation.',
        choice2: ' It is specific to a single service.',
        choice3: ' The SDP ID is locally unique.',
        choice4: ' LDP can be used as the signaling protocol.',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "3. Which of the following is not an accurate description of a VPN?",
        choice1: ' A series of point-to-point tunnels configured on client equipment',
        choice2: ' A tunnel technology created in a provider network',
        choice3: ' A function of MPLS networks to create private communities of users',
        choice4: ' Any network that includes encryption',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "4. Which of the following is false regarding LDP?",
        choice1: ' It is used to define unidirectional paths through the network.',
        choice2: ' It is a protocol specifically intended for label distribution.',
        choice3: ' It is the only method for distributing labels in an MPLS network.',
        choice4: ' It describes a path through the MPLS network based on the IGP path',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "5. Which of the following term–definition pairs is incorrect?",
        choice1: ' Push—Add a label',
        choice2: ' Swap—Replace a label',
        choice3: ' Label distribution protocol—Series of labels and next-hop interfaces',
        choice4: ' Pop—Remove a label',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        " 6. The most commonly used label distribution protocol is ______.",
        choice1: ' OSPF',
        choice2: ' BGP',
        choice3: ' LDP',
        choice4: ' RIP',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "7. Which of the following is not a type of VPN?",
        choice1: ' VPWS',
        choice2: ' VPNM',
        choice3: ' VPLS',
        choice4: ' VPRN',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "8. A VPN that provides a simple point-to-point service between two destinations. is a ______.",
        choice1: ' VPNM',
        choice2: ' VPLS',
        choice3: ' VPWS',
        choice4: ' None of the above',
        answer: 3,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "9. The VPN service that must maintain a table of MAC addresses is ______. ",
        choice1: ' VPWS',
        choice2: ' VPLS',
        choice3: ' VPRN',
        choice4: ' Both A and B ',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "10. The VPN service that requires encryption is ______.",
        choice1: ' VPRN',
        choice2: ' VPNM',
        choice3: ' VPLS',
        choice4: ' None of the above',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "11. The VPN service that appears to the customer as a private routed network is ______",
        choice1: ' VPNM',
        choice2: ' VPRN',
        choice3: ' VPLS',
        choice4: ' VPWS',
        answer: 2,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "12. As a packet traverses an MPLS network, it passes through a router that removes one label and replaces it with another. The router it passed through was a ______ router.",
        choice1: ' PE',
        choice2: ' CE',
        choice3: ' LER',
        choice4: ' P',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "13. A packet arrives at a router with a label, and the router cannot perform any operations on it. The router is most likely a ______.",
        choice1: ' LSR',
        choice2: ' PE',
        choice3: ' LER',
        choice4: ' None of the above',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "14. In an MPLS network, the customer routers have no knowledge of how the MPLS features are implementechoice4: ' The benefits of this include ______.",
        choice1: ' It makes CE configuration easier.',
        choice2: ' It allows for very scalable VPN solutions.',
        choice3: ' It lowers CE management overhead.',
        choice4: ' All of the above',
        answer: 4,
        },							
        {
        question:
        "15. The relationship between LDP and an IGP is best described as.",
        choice1: ' LDP paths are preferred over IGP routes.',
        choice2: ' LDP uses IGP next-hop information.',
        choice3: ' LDP re-distributes labels into IGP.',
        choice4: ' IGP tags network destinations with LDP information',
        answer: 2,
    
    
	
        }
    
]

const SCORE_POINTS = 1
const MAX_QUESTIONS = 20

startGame = () => {
    questionCounter = 0
    score = 0
    availableQuestions = [...questions]
    getNewQuestion()
}

getNewQuestion = () => {
    if(availableQuestions.length === 0 || questionCounter > MAX_QUESTIONS) {
        localStorage.setItem('mostRecentScore', score)

        return window.location.assign('/end.html')
    }

    questionCounter++
    progressText.innerText = `Question ${questionCounter} of ${MAX_QUESTIONS}`
    progressBarFull.style.width = `${(questionCounter/MAX_QUESTIONS) * 100}%`
    
    const questionsIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * availableQuestions.length)
    currentQuestion = availableQuestions[questionsIndex]
    question.innerText = currentQuestion.question

    choices.forEach(choice => {
        const number = choice.dataset['number']
        choice.innerText = currentQuestion['choice' + number]
    })

    availableQuestions.splice(questionsIndex, 1)

    acceptingAnswers = true
}

choices.forEach(choice => {
    choice.addEventListener('click', e => {
        if(!acceptingAnswers) return

        acceptingAnswers = false
        const selectedChoice = e.target
        const selectedAnswer = selectedChoice.dataset['number']

        let classToApply = selectedAnswer == currentQuestion.answer ? 'correct' : 'incorrect'

        if(classToApply === 'correct') {
            incrementScore(SCORE_POINTS)
        }

        selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.add(classToApply)

        setTimeout(() => {
            selectedChoice.parentElement.classList.remove(classToApply)
            getNewQuestion()

        }, 1000)
    })
})

incrementScore = num => {
    score +=num
    scoreText.innerText = score
}

startGame()